Jostine Fei Ho

Technical Skills

Programming Languages

Python: pandas, numpy, scipy, skleam, matplotlib Web-scraping, REST API: beautifulsoup, flask Matlab, C++

Database & Engineering

SQL, NoSQL: MongoDB
Distributed Systems:
Hadoop MapReduce, Spark
Cloud Computing:
AWS EC2, GPU computing

Application Skills

Machine Learning

Supervised learning:

Regressions, SVIVI, PCA Boosting Random fores

Unsupervised learning:

Clustering, Recommenders

Deep Learning:

Convolutional neural networks

Statistical Modeling

A/B testing
Cross validation
Bootstrap sampling
Parametric inference (MLE)
Bayesian optimization
Cost-benefit analysis

Contact Info

- (617) 792-5172
- iostine.ho@gmail.com
- linkedin.com/in/jostinefho
- (n) github.com/JostineHo

Summary

Machine learning scientist passionate about changing the world with deep learning and predictive modeling. Analytical thinking and attention to detail honed through engineering and research background. Energetic self-starter who can work independently to solve real-world problems. Ability to prioritize tasks and support team in fast-paced agile environment.

Relevant Experience

Galvanize Inc., Austin, TexasData Science Fellow (May - August 2016)

Gained 600+ hrs of hands-on experience in latest data science tools:

- Predicting Topic of new articles: launched Spark clusters on AWS, implemented text processing using RDDs, clustered large Wikipedia corpus with MLlib in PySpark, and built topic classification model
- Movie Recommender System: built item-item collaborative filtering with MovieLens users' ratings, discovered latent features, validated predictions with holdout set, and personalized recommendations
- Fraud Detection: performed feature engineering on event ticketing data, trained classifier to determine fraud transactions, and deployed model by building REST API for real-time stream of event transactions
- Facial Emotion Recognition: trained computer vision model using deep convolutional neural network, built image processing pipeline (OpenCV), deployed REST API with database (MongoDB), and partnered with web dev to create interactive web app: mememoji.me. Project documentation: github.com/JostineHo/mememoji

The University of Texas at Austin, Austin, Texas Research Scientist/Engineer Assistant (2015 - 2016)

- Engineered pH-triggered polymer sealant to remediate well leakage
- Developed polymer injection/placement model for field operation
- Showcased technology at major oil & gas conferences (ATCE, CCUS)
- Reduced remediation cost and resulted in joint industry application

Graduate Research Assistant (2012 - 2015)

- Simulated subsurface fluid injection for oil recovery maximization
- Managed and trained undergraduate engineers in performing high-temperature/pressure experiments to validate model simulation

Statoil Svalex Arctic Expedition, Svalbard, NorwayExpedition Researcher (August 2013)

- Collaborated in multidisciplinary team led by Statoil R&D division
- Analyzed regional well-logs to map formation and estimate reserve
- Designed novel drilling strategies applicable to Arctic environment
- Delivered risks and benefit analysis for Svalbard field development

Harvard University, Cambridge, Massachusetts Fellow Research Assistant (2011 - 2012)

VE RI

- Reviewed patient data for socioeconomic disparities cancer mortality
- Assessed evacuation strategies following Fukushima nuclear disaster

Education



The University of Texas at Austin

Dec 2015

M.S. in Petroleum & Geosystems Engineering



National Cheng Kung University, Taiwan

Jun 2011

B.S. in Resources Engineering